The Doctor will save me.
The Doctor will save me...
Excuse me, I'm going to need my inhaler.
Any second now, you're going
to stop that countdown.
Both of you. Together.
And then you're going to negotiate
the most perfect treaty of all time.
Safeguards all round,
completely fair on both sides.
- And the key to perfect negotiation?
- Not knowing what side you're on.
So, for the next few hours,
until we decide to let you out...
No-one in this room will be able
to remember if they're human...
.. or Zygon. Whoops-a-daisy!
Cancel the detonation!
Hello.
- Do you want to...?
- No, you can, if you...
Shall we do it together?
- Operation Double.
- The Zygon peace treaty.
- I'm Osgood.
- I'm also Osgood.
Remember that. It'll be important later.
Operation Double is a covert operation,
outside of normal UNIT strictures,
to resettle and rehouse
- an alien race in secrecy on planet Earth.
- With UNIT's help,
20 million Zygons have been
allowed to take human form,
been dispersed around the world,
and are now living amongst us.
We're making this in case
something goes wrong.
In case UNIT is infiltrated.
In case something occurs
to unmask the Zygons.
Or in case one or both of us dies.
The Zygons are a peaceful race.
Their shape-changing ability
should not be considered a weapon.
It's a survival mechanism.
They embed themselves in other cultures,
and live out their lives in their
new bodies in peace and harmony...
mainly.
Any race is capable of
the best and the worst.
Every race is peaceful and warlike.
- Good and evil.
- My race is no exception.
And neither is mine.
If one Zygon goes rogue...
Or one human...
.. then the ceasefire will break.
- That's why the Doctor left us this.
- He called it the Osgood Box.
If you've been paying attention,
you'll be able to guess why.
- This is the last resort.
- The final sanction.
Pray this box is never needed.
Because if it is, that means
the ceasefire is breaking...
And with 20 million shape-changing Zygons
dispersed around the world...
.. that is the Nightmare Scenario.
Ah!
Come on, kids, no pushing!
'Hi, this is Clara Oswald.
I'm probably on the Tube
'or in outer space. Leave a message!'
Hello, it's Doctor Disco.
I'm in the 21st century.
I don't know what month.
I'm staking out some of the most
dangerous creatures imaginable.
Operating under deep cover.
Trying not to attract suspicion.
Give me a call, Clara. Nightmare Scenario.
I'm worried.
OK. Hey, Monster High and Cinderella.
Down off the monkey bars.
Listen to me. We've got to talk.
Get me Colonel Walsh.
And I need you to coordinate
the Operation Double locations.
There are 20 million Zygons!
And most of the data was with...
her.
Do what you can. Start with any
that have intelligence flags
from the past six months.
Walsh coming through.
- Walsh. Turmezistan.
- Any new arrivals?
One. The pictures aren't very good.
Can you zoom in on the prisoner?
It's her.
Get into her files. We have to
assume they've been compromised.
Too late. The encryption
system's already been hacked.
And they've sent through another video.
Look, I admire you, OK?
I think you're ingenious --
pretending to be a couple of
seven-year-olds is a splendid way
to conceal your blobbiness.
But let's not pretend.
You're very blobby.
In fact, you two are the big blobs.
And you are not patrolling the ceasefire.
Fine. Fine, bury your heads.
Listen to me. Listen!
There are other factions.
I know that there are other
blobby factions you don't control.
They're planning something.
And if we don't get together and stop it,
it'll be the end of this. Of all of you.
This is our jurisdiction, Doctor.
These are our creatures. We
are close to finding them.
They are our children, and
we will deal with them.
Your kids are out of control.
I'm taking this out of your hands.
Don't even think about going anywhere.
Are you phoning me with
your backside again,
or are you really sending
me a distress signal?
I'm really sending you a distress signal.
They've kidnapped Osgood and
they've stolen the location
of every Zygon on Earth.
Doctor, the ceasefire's broken down.
Hey! Away! Away!
Get those kids out of the way!
Out of the way! Out of
the way! Out of the way!
Move! Out of the way!
UNIT troops will be destroyed
wherever they are in the world.
The enemies of our race will be destroyed
The war is about to begin.
There will be truth...
.. or there will be consequences.
'Hi, this is Clara Oswald.
I'm probably on the Tube
'or in outer space. Leave a message!'
Call me now.
'Hello, it's Doctor Disco...'
Hello. Oh, hello.
Sandeep, hello.
- You OK?
- I can't find my mummy and daddy.
Well, why don't you wait here, and
I can go see if I can find them?
Hello?
Oh, sorry -- erm,
your little boy is out there.
He couldn't find you.
Daddy's here!
We can take him.
- Is... Is he OK?
- Everything's fine.
Did you just call yourself "Doctor Disco"?
This is where the Zygon High
Command had their secret base.
A junior school?
Terms of the settlement,
Operation Double, were these --
20 million Zygons, the entire hatchery,
were allowed to be born
and to stay on Earth.
They were permitted to
permanently take up the form
of the nearest available
human beings -- in this case,
a large percentage of the
population of the UK.
You left us with an
impossible situation, Doctor.
Yes, I know. It's called peace.
What about the two little girl commanders?
Weren't they helping you?
They've been almost impossible
to deal with since Osgood left.
Secretive, uncommunicative.
We've known there's something
going on -- some radicalisation,
some revolution in the younger brood.
They said they had it under control.
The Zygon command centre.
That's the control polyp
for all Zygons on Earth.
It's horrible.
Could you...? Would you mind? Thank you.
If this has been compromised,
the Zygons are wide open.
They'll be starting to panic.
Starting to worry.
Doctor, do you want to
be alone with that thing?
It's a command computer.
You operate it by titivating the fronds.
Are you enjoying that?!
I snogged a Zygon once. Old habits...
Still got the old magic.
So, Osgood's been kidnapped,
right? I thought Osgood was dead.
There've always been two of
her, ever since the ceasefire.
- We never knew which one was real.
- Both of them.
- OK, which one was Zygon.
They would have maintained a live link --
they were both Zygon and
human at the same time.
They not only administered the
peace, they were the peace.
When the other Osgood died,
the survivor went pretty
much mad with grief.
Then she just disappeared --
went undercover in the States.
Now, of course, the rebels have her.
Ah! OK.
Zygons hatched and dispersed all over --
but something's gone wrong.
Mexico border, North Asia,
West Africa, Australia...
Panic. Paranoia.
What would happen if
they knew who we were?
We've received another video.
That's the Zygon High Command.
It's Jemima and Claudette.
We have been betrayed.
We were sold.
Our rights were violated.
We demand the right to be ourselves.
Normalise.
Normalise!
We are now the Zygon High Command.
All traitors will die.
Truth or consequences.
So, we have a Zygon
revolution on our hands.
- We need to open negotiations.
- I'm not negotiating with them.
As far as they're concerned,
everyone's a traitor.
If you're not going to negotiate,
what are you going to do?
They're holed up in this
settlement in Turmezistan --
it's where they've taken Osgood. I'm
going to order Colonel Walsh to bomb it.
Isn't there a solution that
doesn't involve bombing everyone?
The treaty's been comprehensively
violated, Doctor.
This is a splinter group. The rest
of the Zygons, the vast majority --
they want to live in peace.
You start bombing them,
you'll radicalise the lot.
That's exactly what the
splinter group wants.
"Truth or consequences" --
what exactly does that mean?
It's just the usual kind of nonsense
these idiots call themselves.
- It's in New Mexico.
- What?
It's a town in New Mexico
-- Truth or Consequences.
They renamed it after a TV
show, for a bet or something.
It's a Trivial Pursuit question.
I used to memorise Trivial
Pursuit questions so I could win.
That's the last place we received
signal from Osgood's phone,
isn't it? New Mexico.
OK. Kate Stewart, no bombs for
you. Go to Truth or Consequences.
See what you can find out. The
Doctor will go to Turmezistan.
Negotiate peace, rescue
Osgood, and prevent this war,
cos that's what he does.
Clara, Jac -- you stay here.
This is your country --
protect it from the scary monsters.
- And also from the Zygons.
- Fine.
Oh, and do you still have
the presidential aircraft?
I thought you didn't like
being President of the World.
No, but I like poncing
about in a big plane.
How many troops do you have?
Not many.
Usually on bigger cases we can
draft in from the regular army.
We can't do that now.
The secrecy of the project
has to be maintained.
You got any snazzy weapons?
There was an attempted
Zygon invasion before,
in the '70s, '80s.
One of our staff was a naval surgeon.
Worked at Porton Down
on the captured Zygons.
Developed Z-67.
It's a nerve gas. Unravels their DNA.
Basically, turns them inside out.
Where do you keep it?
We don't. It was taken --
- the formula, the lot.
- Who took it?
Somebody with a Tardis.
They're ready for you, ma'am.
Keep in touch.
Oh, I just need to swing by
home and grab a couple of things.
Yeah, course.
Quick, before someone sees us!
It's really slow. We can
catch them. (Come on!)
- It's slower than usual.
- What's wrong with it?
- Is there a cellar, or somewhere
else they could've gone? - No.
Ugh, what is that?
No, don't!
I think we need to get
some reinforcements.
Approaching target at 1-00-65-12.
Confirm strike order.
Order confirmed.
At ease.
I'm the President of the World.
I'm here to rescue people
and generally establish
happiness all over the place.
The Doctor. Doctor Funkenstein.
- Yes, we know who you are.
- Going to strike altitude.
What's going on here?
Fun and games?
We're 700 metres lower, 700
metres lower than planned. Over.
You're not bombing that town. That's
where they're holding my friend.
They're dangerous. And your
friend is almost certainly dead.
I'm not going to allow them to disperse.
You can't track a shape-shifter.
Visual on the target.
Confirm strike.
Colonel!
Confirm strike!
Confirm strike.
Strike aborted. Strike aborted.
Well, that's interesting.
Hello?
You one of them?
I'm a friend. I've come to help.
Alone?
Have you come to help alone?
What happened here?
You must have brought backup.
Where's your backup?
- Tell me!
- First, tell me why I need it.
We think it's a Zygon training camp.
We never see more than one or two
of them outside at any one time.
But they always take different shapes --
we don't know how many there really are.
We don't know how they come and go
-- whether they go through tunnels,
or whether they turn into dogs
and run out across the hills.
So, that's what we'll find out.
We should have that gas.
We should be able to rip them inside out.
Colonel, take it easy. They're
trying to unsettle you.
They're trying to make
you paranoid and panicked.
Any living thing in this world,
including my family and friends,
could turn into a Zygon and
kill me, any second now.
It's not paranoia when it's real.
I've been looking into this.
There have been reports all over
London of strange activity in lifts.
I've patched into CCTV
from Scotland Yard --
all the elevators I can find.
Now, this is SOAS.
People dragging bundles.
They go down, down, down,
a few minutes go by. And then...
.. they're all gone.
There is something very wrong
happening underneath London.
The Brits came two years ago.
We didn't want them. They just...
They just turned up.
No jobs. Nowhere to live. No money.
And they were... They were odd.
They started getting into fights.
Couple of them got killed.
More than a couple. What happened here?
After the murders, they
started banding together.
And then, one day, one of them changed.
Changed?
One of them was walking down West Main,
and suddenly,
it turned into a...
.. a reptile.
They just came for us.
They turned into monsters
and they CAME for us.
And we couldn't fight them.
You can't tell who's who.
They can turn your own family against you.
Have you seen her?
Yeah, she was here. She was at
the motel, asking questions.
Before...
- Everybody's gone.
- Where?
'OK, listen carefully.
Once we get to the village
'we have a 30-minute window
before the airstrike.'
We all know what a rabbit
warren this place is,
but we've got intel they're
holed up inside the church.
Hitchley, you take the front,
storm it, draw their fire,
- the Doctor and I will take the back.
- This is our object.
We need to get her back. Safely.
Try to kill as few of them as possible,
I need have to have
someone to negotiate with.
You know what they're capable
of. Do not fall victim to it.
- Truck open. Code Green.
- Let's move out!
Come out! Throw down your weapons!
Come out! We have you surrounded!
COME OUT OF THERE!
Come out, we have you surrounded!
I don't have any weapons. Please.
Take aim. On my command.
No. No, don't, please.
Johnny...
you don't understand.
You're not my mother, don't use my name.
They took us here.
They came to the house and took us.
They took your sister.
- Me.
- Stay where you are.
It's not us who are the impostors.
Don't let them trick you.
It's your commanders, your
chief -- they're the aliens.
'Do not fall victim!'
Ask her some details. She's a copy --
ask something only your mum could know.
- Mom, I'm going to have to ask you
some questions. - Don't do this.
You know it's me.
Don't let them trick you.
- Date and place of my birth.
- They brought us here,
they're using us against you.
I'm scared.
Please, I'm so scared.
Name of my favourite teddy bear.
I don't remember.
I'm sorry, I don't.
Don't kill me because I can't remember!
Hitchley!
Stay back!
All of you, stay back from them!
That is not your mother,
it's an alien hostile.
We're not those creatures, we're hostages.
Kill it!
I can prove it. I can prove who we are.
Just come inside, I'll show you.
Don't go in there.
- Please.
- You're not my mom!
Oh, God, you're going to kill me.
Mom, please...
You are, you're going to kill me.
I love you.
I forgive you and I love you.
Do it!
- What proof? - Don't go in
there, you're going to your death!
- Hitchley, kill it.
- Let's go.
Over and out, ma'am.
Dammit.
DAMMIT!
This is pointless! Just
let me go in and talk!
They've executed my men.
Where are the Zygons?
We need to bomb the
hell out of this place.
It's INFESTED with these things.
We can't tell who the enemy is any more,
we can't count them and
we can't track them!
I'm not going to let you do that.
I just lost my men,
I'll quite happily bomb
the hell out of anywhere.
We need to move. Strike's on its way.
- I need to find Osgood.
- You've got ten minutes.
- Help! Help!
- Osgood!
- Doctor!
- Doctor, I'm here!
Osgood!
I'm down here!
- Osgood!
- Doctor!
Doctor!
- Osgood!
Got to get you out. They're
going to bomb this place.
What do the Zygons want?
They're training, practising new skills
-- doctor what are you doing here?
Rescuing you. In quite a
dashing way, I might add.
They fled through the tunnels.
They're going back to the UK.
If you're here, they've got you out
of the way. Who's left in the UK?
- Clara.
- Clara!
Oh, hello.
They've started.
So much for "ten minutes"(!)
You found something? What?
What do you want me to see?
Oh, God.
W-Were those all people?
It's an odd world nowadays, isn't it?
It's always been an odd world.
Mm. I mean, doesn't it feel, sometimes,
that things are coming to an end?
Everything's just going nuts.
You're middle-aged, that's
what it is. No offence.
Everybody middle-aged always thinks
the world's about to come to an end.
Never does.
It's here.
Oh, my God.
'Hi, this is Clara Oswald.
'I'm probably on the tube or in
outer space. Leave a message!'
Can you change your
voicemail message, please,
it's getting very boring.
Oh, I see you've accessorised it.
Yes.
- The old question marks.
- You used to wear question marks.
Oh, I know, yes, I did.
They were nice. Why don't
you wear them any more?
Oh, I do.
I've got question mark underpants.
Makes one wonder what the question is.
Which one are you?
Human or Zygon?
- I don't answer that question.
- Why not?
Because there isn't a question
to answer. I don't accept it.
My sister and I were the living
embodiment of the peace we made.
I will give all the lives
I have to protect it.
You want to know who I am, Doctor?
I am the peace.
I am Human AND Zygon.
Like a hybrid.
A hybrid, if you like.
Well, I'm proud to know you, Osgood.
And I promise that I won't tell
anyone... that you're a human.
Zygons need to keep the
human original alive
to refresh the body print.
If you were a Zygon,
you'd've changed back within
days of your sister's death.
Those were the old rules.
Before Zygons could pluck
loved ones from your memory
and wear their faces.
Zygons only need to
keep the original alive
if they need more information from them.
If the interrogation is over...
then the original can die.
Oh, my God.
These are Zygon pods.
- I think you might be right.
- About what?
The end of the world.
Bit of first-things-first-ness.
What's your name?
My name's -- well...
you can call me the Doctor.
But then you knew that, didn't you?
You want something.
What is it?
You are the President of the World?
I suppose so.
We want... the world.
OK. It looks like whole buildings
full of people have been pinched.
In fact, it looks like a
whole London full of people
have been pinched. But we've got
here early, they're still growing.
We've have to neutralise
these before they hatch.
Take your positions.
Do you know what?
I'm enjoying this.
- Clara.
- What?
We don't know that's what these are.
Oh, come on. These are eggs,
or pods, or whatever -- look.
Oh, my God, that's me.
I think we should wait.
Look, they're here,
they're growing duplicates of us.
We have to destroy them.
I've seen this happen before.
It happened to that little boy,
they took his parents
and then they took him.
But I don't see how these ARE duplicates,
that's not how Zygons work,
they don't grow duplicates,
THEY kidnap the original, so these...
These... ARE the humans.
Retreat.
Retreat! This is a trap!
This is an ambush!
No...
Oh, no, Miss Oswald, please. Please!
Kill the traitors.
Is he OK?
Hello, Clara.
My name is Bonnie.
We want the truth of who we are
to be acknowledged.
We want to live as ourselves.
At any cost. We want a home.
Well, you can't have the United Kingdom.
There's already people living there.
They'll think you're going
to pinch their benefits.
We're already there, Doctor.
The invasion's already taken place,
bit by bit, over the last year.
We've won the first battle.
And now, we are going to begin the war.
There's hundreds more.
They killed everybody.
We have to find out what forms they
took, how many of them there were.
- How did this happen?
- Somebody once caught the briefest of glimpses
of a Zygon in its proper form.
A child...
who hadn't learned to
preserve its body print...
.. who had been left alone
to learn these things for itself.
And then word went round
these primitives...
- that we were monsters.
- "We"?
There isn't any backup, is there?
I just had to be sure.
'Commander calling Truth or
Consequences. What is your status?'
'Repeat, Commander calling
Truth or Consequences.
- 'What is your status?'
- Commander...
UNIT neutralised in North America,
Truth or consequences.
'Copy that.'
Bonnie speaking. UNIT
neutralised in the UK.
More or less.
Answer it. Say goodbye.
This plane will never land.
Really. Clara?
Doctor.
- Clara?
- There you are.
- Clara, I'm glad you're OK. Listen...
- You're breaking up.
The invasion has happened. You're
probably surrounded by Zygons.
Get to the Tardis, get yourself safe.
And, apparently, my plane
is never going to land
- but let's see what we're going
to do about that. - I'm sorry,
but Clara's dead.
Kate Stewart is dead,
the UNIT troops are all dead.
Truth or consequences.